<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-13T08:35:22-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paulus Schoutsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nest in the house!]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/13/nest-in-da-house/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T08:29:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/13/nest-in-da-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For thet majority of its existence, Home Assistant primary focus was on presence detection, lights and switches. But not anymore as we&rsquo;re expanding the supported devices. Today, we&rsquo;re proud to introduce Nest Thermostat integration for Home Assistant contributed by <a href="https://github.com/sfiorini">Stefano Fiorini</a>!</p>

<p class='img'>
  <img src='https://home-assistant.io/images/screenshots/nest-thermostat-card.png' />
</p>


<p>The new integration exists out of two parts: a generic thermostat component and a Nest platform implementation. The initial version implements provides a read-only card and services to control it. The plan is in the future to add temperature and away mode controls from the thermostat card and more info dialog. Internally, we are using the Python package <a href="https://github.com/jkoelker/python-nest">python-nest by jkoelker</a> to talk to the Nest.</p>

<p>If you own a Nest thermostat, add the following lines to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>[thermostat]
</span><span class='line'>platform=nest
</span><span class='line'>username=YOUR_USERNAME
</span><span class='line'>password=YOUR_PASSWORD</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrapping your setup with Discovery]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/11/bootstrapping-your-setup-with-discovery/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-11T21:49:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/11/bootstrapping-your-setup-with-discovery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most people do not like configuring things. Things just have to work, out of the box. Reaching this scenario is the goal of what we are about to introduce: our new discovery component.</p>

<p>The discovery component will scan the WiFi network from time to time for connected zeroconf/mDNS and uPnP devices. The intial introduction is mainly focussed on getting the right architecture in place and discovers Belkin WeMo switches and Google Chromecasts connected to your network. When found, it will load and notify the appropritate component and it will be ready to use within seconds.</p>

<p>Most devices still require some sort of interaction from the user after being discovered - be it a button being pressed or some sort of authentication. This is a challenge that will be solved in the future.</p>

<p>To enable the discovery component, add the following to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>[discovery]</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>A new <a href="https://home-assistant.io/developers/add_new_platform.html#discovery">discovery section</a> has been added to the Adding a new platform page with instructions how to make your platform discoverable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello PushBullet, nice talking to you]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/04/hey-pushbullet-nice-talking-to-you/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T13:29:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/04/hey-pushbullet-nice-talking-to-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that was missing in Home Assistant for a while was a way to communicate with users. Wouldn&rsquo;t it be nice to get a message when important events happen like the lights being turned on while no one is home? Since the Home Assistant frontend runs as a web application on the phone, we have no way to bring ourselves to the front. This is where the new notify component comes in, powered by PushBullet.</p>

<p>The new notify component will take in messages and tells them to the user. For now this will be powered by the very awesome <a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/">PushBullet</a> but any other messaging platform can be easily added.</p>

<p class='img'>
  <img src='https://home-assistant.io/images/screenshots/pushbullet_moto360.png' />
  A message triggered by the simple_alarm component is shown by PushBullet on the Moto360.
</p>


<p>Read on to learn how to enable the notify component and integrate it with other components.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Enabling the notify component</h3>

<p>To enable the new notify component, add the following to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>[notify]
</span><span class='line'>platform=pushbullet
</span><span class='line'>api_key=ABCDEFGHJKLMNOPQRSTUVXYZ</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You can get your api key from <a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/account">your account page on PushBullet.com</a>.</p>

<h3>Sending messages from your component</h3>

<p>To be able to send messages, the notify component has to be loaded and initialized successfully.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='python'><span class='line'><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">homeassistant.loader</span> <span class="kn">as</span> <span class="nn">loader</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">setup</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">hass</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">config</span><span class="p">):</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">notify</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">loader</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">get_component</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#39;notify&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">notify</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">send_message</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">hass</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s">&quot;Hello from my component!&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Control, Automation &amp; the Smart Home]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2014/12/26/home-control-home-automation-and-the-smart-home/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-26T10:23:13-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2014/12/26/home-control-home-automation-and-the-smart-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The internet has been buzzing over the last year about home automation. A lot of different terms fly around like the internet of things, home automation and the smart home.
This article will try to explain how they all relate.</p>

<p>The first thing to introduce is the <strong>Internet of Things</strong> (IoT). This refers to a new generation of devices that cannot only be controlled by humans via buttons or remotes but also provide an interface to communicate with other devices and applications. For example, an IoT-capable coffee machine could receive commands to create different types of coffee and be able to broadcast the amount of water left in its resevoir.</p>

<p>There is no widely adopted open standard for smart device communication. This prevents a lot of devices to communicate with one another. And even if they could, most devices are not designed to manage other devices. To solve this we need a device to be able to communicate with and manage all these connected devices. This device is called a <strong>hub</strong>.</p>

<p>As a bare minimum a hub has to keep track of the state of each device and should be able to control them if possible. For example, it has to know which lights are on or off and offer a way to control the lights. For a sensor it only has to know the value. A hub with these capabilities offers <strong>home control</strong>.</p>

<p class='img'>
  <a href='https://home-assistant.io/images/screenshots/nexus_7_dashboard.png'>
    <img alt='Hub dashboard example'
         src='https://home-assistant.io/images/screenshots/nexus_7_dashboard.png' />
  </a>
  Example of a hub&#8217;s dashboard. Showing the state of 2 persons, 4 lights and the sun.
</p>


<!--more-->


<p>A step up from home control is to have the user setup triggers to send commands based on information in the home control layer. For example, to turn on the lights when a person arrives home. A hub with these capabilities is capable of <strong>home automation</strong>.</p>

<p>Most hubs on the market today offer this in various degrees of functionality and usability. Some IoT-capable devices offer this too, but only control themselves and are usually limited to location and time-based events.</p>

<p>The last category, and this is still very much in the future, is the <strong>smart home</strong>. A self-learning and adopting system that will decide which events should impact other devices.</p>

<p>An example of a smart home in action is that it observes that when person A comes home, the lights in the living room and the kitchen switch on. While if person B comes home, the lights in the living room and the study room are switched on. The next time person A or B comes home, the smart home will turn on its preferred lights without any configuration being set by the user.</p>

<p>A glimpse today at how the future can look is the <a href="https://nest.com/">Nest thermostat</a>. A thermostat smart enough to learn your schedule and adjust its own temperature accordingly.</p>

<p>All this results in the following overview of Home Automation.</p>

<p class='img'>
  <a href='https://home-assistant.io/images/architecture/home_automation_landscape.png'>
    <img alt='Home Automation landscape'
         src='https://home-assistant.io/images/architecture/home_automation_landscape.png' />
  </a>
  Overview of the home automation landscape.
</p>


<h3>Challenges</h3>

<p>You are probably wondering, this all seems relatively simple, why don&rsquo;t I have my very own smart home yet? There are a couple of challenges today that keep us from stepping into the future.</p>

<h4>More Internet of Things-capable devices</h4>

<p>The majority of the IoT products out there are either lights, switches or presence detection. That&rsquo;s not enough for your home to be very smart about. We need televisions, fridges, ovens and more to join the party to increase the number of devices that we can control.</p>

<h4>More data</h4>

<p>Most first generation IoT devices are only exposing information that is needed for controlling it. We need to be able to track all interactions with each device for our smart home to learn how interaction with devices influence other things. For example, we need to be able to track how many cups of coffee were made or how often the fridge was open. This will increase the information flow and open up a whole bunch of new possibilities. For example, the smart home can order new coffee when you&rsquo;re running low.</p>

<h4>Easy to use, open software that we can trust</h4>

<p>To increase adoption we will need people to trust their smart home system. It will be very tough to convince people to upgrade all their devices and upload all interactions with each of them to the cloud. This data could reveal their whole life including all bad habits. That&rsquo;s why such a system should be simple and open-source so people can validate that their data generated at home stays home.</p>

<p>Anoter important booster for adoption is that the software should be easy to set up and use by the average user. A lot of people are not burning their hands yet on Home Automation because they are scared of configurating it.</p>

<p>Home Assistant is trying to be this software. It is not there yet but trying hard. Device discovery and a user interface for configuring home automation are problems we hope to tackle in 2015 while not sacrificing any modularity or usability.</p>

<p>Happy new year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website launched!]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2014/12/18/website-launched/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-18T23:24:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2014/12/18/website-launched</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally took the time to setup a simple website to help people getting started with Home Assistant. The process was super smooth thanks to the great tools <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> and <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> and the great services <a href="https://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> and <a href="https://cloudflare.com">CloudFlare</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
