<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: core | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/core/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-16T07:13:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paulus Schoutsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UTC & Time zone awareness]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/05/09/utc-time-zone-awareness/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T23:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/05/09/utc-time-zone-awareness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have recently merged code to refactor Home Assistant to use only UTC times internally. A much needed refactor. I’ve added some extra test coverage to time sensitive parts to ensure stability. The code has been live in the dev branch for the last 9 days and will be soon released to the master branch.</p>

<p>From now on all internal communication will be done in UTC: time changed events, datetime attributes of states, etc. To get the current time in UTC you can call <code>homeassistant.util.dt.utcnow()</code>. This is a timezone aware UTC datetime object. <a href="https://github.com/balloob/home-assistant/blob/dev/homeassistant/util/dt.py"><code>homeassistant.util.dt</code></a> is a new util package with date helpers.</p>

<p>There is also such a thing as local time. Local time is based on the time zone that you have setup in your <code>configuration.yaml</code>. Local times should only be used for user facing information: logs, frontend and automation settings in <code>configuration.yaml</code>.</p>

<h3>Setting up your time zone</h3>
<p>Setting up a time zone happens in <code>configuration.yaml</code>. If you have no time zone setup, it will be auto detected using the existing detection code using <a href="https://freegeoip.net">freegeoip.net</a>. You can find a list of compatible time zones on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_tz_database_time_zones">Wikipedia</a>.</p>

<div class="highlighter-coderay"><div class="CodeRay">
  <div class="code"><pre><span class="key">homeassistant</span>:
  <span class="key">time_zone</span>: <span class="string"><span class="content">America/Los_Angeles</span></span>
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>

<h3>Compatibility</h3>
<p>The changes to the code are mostly backwards compatible. The old <code>hass.track_time_change</code> and <code>hass.track_point_in_time</code> use now internally two new methods: <code>hass.track_utc_time_change</code> and <code>hass.track_point_in_utc_time</code>. The usage of the old methods have not changed and should be backwards compatible.</p>

<p>This refactor adds a new migration for the database adding a <code>utc_offset</code> column to events and states. This information is currently not used but can prove useful in the future when we start analyzing the historical data.</p>

<h3><a class='title-link' name='backwards-incompatible-stuff' href='#backwards-incompatible-stuff'></a> Backwards incompatible stuff </h3>

<p>All built-in components have been upgraded. The following list is only for people that run custom components:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>hass.track_time_change</code> and <code>hass.track_point_in_time</code> will now return a time zone aware datetime object. Python does not allow comparing a naive with an aware datetime object.</li>
  <li>the sun attributes for rising and setting are now in UTC. The methods <code>sun.next_rising(hass)</code> and <code>sun.next_setting(hass)</code> are backwards compatible, just be careful if you used to read the raw attributes.</li>
  <li>the API sends all times in UTC. If you use anything else besides the frontend to talk to HA, make sure it handles it differently.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Assistant moving to YAML]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/01/home-assistant-migrating-to-yaml/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T11:38:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/01/home-assistant-migrating-to-yaml</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Home Assistant is now using <a href="http://yaml.org/">YAML</a> for it’s configuration file. YAML allows the use of lists, which should make the configuration file a bit more flexible and useful. The new configuration file format is backwards compatible with existing components. Because of this, there is no need for component developers to update their components.</p>

<p>The new file is named configuration.yaml and if it can’t be found in your config directory, Home Assistant will instead try to find the old configuration file, home-assistant.conf.</p>

<p>The home-assistant.conf.example has been replaced with an updated <a href="https://github.com/balloob/home-assistant/blob/dev/config/configuration.yaml.example">configuration.yaml.example</a>.</p>

<p>Users of Home Assistant should migrate as the old configuration format is deprecated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
