<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: component | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/component/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-16T07:13:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paulus Schoutsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the past]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/02/08/looking-at-the-past/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T09:01:23-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/02/08/looking-at-the-past</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since the launch of Home Assistant you have been able to track the state of your house. But the view has always been limited to what the current state is. Not what it was. Today we are going to change that by introducing two brand new components:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Recorder component that will record every event to a SQLite database</li>
  <li>History component that will query and aggregate the recorded events</li>
</ul>

<p>By adding this view into the past, we are adding an extra dimension into the state of your house. This brings great new possibilities for future features. The focus of todays release is on getting the recording component to you to start recording and getting some data. To show what is being recorded a view has been added that shows the last 24 hours of your house. Expect more extensive tools to explore your history in the future.</p>

<p>Adding history to the UI was a challenge on itself because the old UI did not support easy navigation. So to add to the awesomeness of this release, Home Assistant also got a face lift.</p>

<p>The history component will be enabled for new users by default. For current users, run <code>scripts/update</code> to upgrade to the latest version and add <code>[history]</code> to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code> file.</p>

<p class="img">
  <a href="/images/screenshots/component_history_24h.png">
    <img src="/images/screenshots/component_history_24h.png" />
  </a>
</p>

<p class="note">
Events are saved in a local database. Google Graphs is used to draw the graph. Drawing is happening 100% in your browser - no data is transfered to anyone at any time.
</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Tracking history is an exciting next step for Home Assistant and will power the next generation of features. Here a list of some of the cool things that can now be build:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Time Machine: explore the state of your house at any point in the past</li>
  <li>Smart Home: analyze behavior and use it to automate your house</li>
  <li>Summarize usage of the different components of your house</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nest in the house!]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/13/nest-in-da-house/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T08:29:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/13/nest-in-da-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For thet majority of its existence, Home Assistant primary focus was on presence detection, lights and switches. But not anymore as we’re expanding the supported devices. Today, we’re proud to introduce Nest Thermostat integration for Home Assistant contributed by <a href="https://github.com/sfiorini">Stefano Fiorini</a>!</p>

<p class="img">
  <img src="/images/screenshots/nest-thermostat-card.png" />
</p>

<p>The new integration exists out of two parts: a generic thermostat component and a Nest platform implementation. The initial version implements provides a read-only card and services to control it. The plan is in the future to add temperature and away mode controls from the thermostat card and more info dialog. Internally, we are using the Python package <a href="https://github.com/jkoelker/python-nest">python-nest by jkoelker</a> to talk to the Nest.</p>

<p>If you own a Nest thermostat, add the following lines to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<div class="highlighter-coderay"><div class="CodeRay">
  <div class="code"><pre>[thermostat]
platform=nest
username=YOUR_USERNAME
password=YOUR_PASSWORD
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrapping your setup with Discovery]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/11/bootstrapping-your-setup-with-discovery/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-11T21:49:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/11/bootstrapping-your-setup-with-discovery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most people do not like configuring things. Things just have to work, out of the box. Reaching this scenario is the goal of what we are about to introduce: our new discovery component.</p>

<p>The discovery component will scan the WiFi network from time to time for connected zeroconf/mDNS and uPnP devices. The intial introduction is mainly focussed on getting the right architecture in place and discovers Belkin WeMo switches and Google Chromecasts connected to your network. When found, it will load and notify the appropritate component and it will be ready to use within seconds.</p>

<p>Most devices still require some sort of interaction from the user after being discovered - be it a button being pressed or some sort of authentication. This is a challenge that will be solved in the future.</p>

<p>To enable the discovery component, add the following to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<div class="highlighter-coderay"><div class="CodeRay">
  <div class="code"><pre>[discovery]
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>

<p>A new <a href="/developers/add_new_platform/#discovery">discovery section</a> has been added to the Adding a new platform page with instructions how to make your platform discoverable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello PushBullet, nice talking to you]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/04/hey-pushbullet-nice-talking-to-you/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T13:29:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/04/hey-pushbullet-nice-talking-to-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that was missing in Home Assistant for a while was a way to communicate with users. Wouldn’t it be nice to get a message when important events happen like the lights being turned on while no one is home? Since the Home Assistant frontend runs as a web application on the phone, we have no way to bring ourselves to the front. This is where the new notify component comes in, powered by PushBullet.</p>

<p>The new notify component will take in messages and tells them to the user. For now this will be powered by the very awesome <a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/">PushBullet</a> but any other messaging platform can be easily added.</p>

<p class="img">
  <img src="/images/screenshots/pushbullet_moto360.png" />
  A message triggered by the simple_alarm component is shown by PushBullet on the Moto360.
</p>

<p>Read on to learn how to enable the notify component and integrate it with other components.</p>

<!--more-->

<h3>Enabling the notify component</h3>

<p>To enable the new notify component, add the following to your <code>home-assistant.conf</code>:</p>

<div class="highlighter-coderay"><div class="CodeRay">
  <div class="code"><pre>[notify]
platform=pushbullet
api_key=ABCDEFGHJKLMNOPQRSTUVXYZ
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>

<p>You can get your api key from <a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/account">your account page on PushBullet.com</a>.</p>

<h3>Sending messages from your component</h3>

<p>To be able to send messages, the notify component has to be loaded and initialized successfully.</p>

<div class="highlighter-coderay"><div class="CodeRay">
  <div class="code"><pre><span class="keyword">import</span> <span class="include">homeassistant.loader</span> <span class="keyword">as</span> loader

<span class="keyword">def</span> <span class="function">setup</span>(hass, config):
    notify = loader.get_component(<span class="string"><span class="delimiter">'</span><span class="content">notify</span><span class="delimiter">'</span></span>)
    notify.send_message(hass, <span class="string"><span class="delimiter">&quot;</span><span class="content">Hello from my component!</span><span class="delimiter">&quot;</span></span>)
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
