<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: release-notes | Home Assistant]]></title>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/categories/release-notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://home-assistant.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-11T19:36:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://home-assistant.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paulus Schoutsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release notes for March 11, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/11/release-notes/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-11T19:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/03/11/release-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has only been a little over a week since Theodor introduced YAML support for Home Assistant but so much has already happened that it is time for a summary of recent changes. Before mentioning the highlights I want to thank <a href="https://github.com/andythigpen">andythigpen</a>, <a href="https://github.com/jamespcole">jamespcole</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theolind">theolind</a> for numerous bug fixes, enhancements and new contributions. Thanks!</p>

<p><strong>Monitor local resources.</strong><br>
Theodor has contributed a new sensor platform to allow you to monitor disk usage, memory usage, CPU usage and running processes. This platform has superseded the process component which is now considered deprecated.</p>

<pre><code class="yaml"># Example configuration.yaml entry
sensor:
  - platform: systemmonitor
    resources:
      - type: disk_use_percent
        arg: /home
      - type: memory_free
      - type: process
        arg: kodi
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Experimental Z-Wave support</strong><br>
There is now experimental support for connecting Z-Wave networks using a Z-Wave USB stick. Right now it only integrates Z-Wave sensors into Home Assistant. Our goal is to get this tested by more people before adding support for other Z-Wave devices.</p>

<p>The new component is built on top of <a href="https://code.google.com/p/python-openzwave/">python-openzwave</a>. This package is currently not distributed on PyPi so we&rsquo;ve added a script <code>scripts/build_python_openzwave</code> to install it on your machine. Alternatively you can use the Docker image which is ready to go.</p>

<p>The development was done using an AEON Z-Wave USB stick and an AEON Z-Wave MultiSensor.</p>

<pre><code class="yaml"># Example configuration.yaml entry
zwave:
  usb_path: /dev/ttyUSB0
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Voice control</strong><br>
An initial version of voice control for Home Assistant has landed. The current implementation consists of two parts.</p>

<p>The first part is a component called <code>conversation</code> that exposes the service <code>conversation/process</code>. This service is capable of processing text and translating them into commands for devices. For now it will only support commands in the format of <code>Turn &lt;Friendly Name&gt; &lt;on/off&gt;</code>.</p>

<p>The second part is an upgrade to the frontend to use the speech-to-text in Chrome to allow users to speak commands. If you&rsquo;re using Chrome, you can test this out in <a href="/demo/">the demo</a>.</p>

<pre><code class="yaml"># Example configuration.yaml entry
conversation:
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release notes for January 24, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/24/release-notes/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-24T18:36:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://home-assistant.io/blog/2015/01/24/release-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have just merged the latest version of the development branch into master. Here are some of the highlights of this release:</p>

<p><strong>Configuration via the frontend</strong><br>
Phliips Hue will now be auto discovered and uses the new <code>configurator</code> component to interact with the user to finish the setup process.</p>

<p><strong>Wink Hub support</strong><br>
Thanks to the work done by John McLaughlin and Geoff Norton we now support the lights, switches and sensors that are connected to the Wink hub.</p>

<p><strong>The getting started guide and component page have been reorganized</strong><br>
The getting started instructions have been split into separate pages per component and a general overview page. The goal is to have a page per component that describes:</p>

<ul>
<li>What it does</li>
<li>How to set it up</li>
<li>Which states it maintains</li>
<li>Which services it provides</li>
<li>Additional development tips</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>More reasonable errors</strong><br>
Home Assistant should now throw better errors and offer solutions if you do not have the right version of Python 3, forgot to clone the git submodules or install the dependencies.</p>

<p><strong>Streamlined first launch</strong><br>
Home Assistant now supports <code>--open-ui</code> and <code>--demo-mode</code> command line properties to open the browser automatically and have something to show. Home Assistant now supports to be run without a password, allowing the interface to login automatically on launch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
